skoolbo.com 2019-03-02

# Skoolbo - Reading, Writing, Numeracy, Languages, Science and more

## Skoolbo Privacy Policy

####  _Policy updated 22nd March 2018_

Skoolbo is committed to ensuring your privacy is protected. Skoolbo collects the minimum amount of information possible for the effective learning management of the Child. 

Personal information related to the child is shared only with the Parent, the Teacher and the School Administrator. Skoolbo will never sell, distribute or lease the User’s personal information to third parties. 

Skoolbo strives to be fully compliant with all appropriate laws such as COPPA in the USA, GDPR in the EEA, Privacy Act in Australia, New Zealand and Canada and PIPEDA in Canada and US federal and national laws of any country in which our users abide. 

The Skoolbo Privacy Policy sets out how Skoolbo Pty Ltd ("Skoolbo") uses and protects the information that you give Skoolbo when you use the “Skoolbo services” available from the domains www.Skoolbo.com, www.Skoolbo.com.au, www.Skoolbo.co.nz, www.Skoolbo.co.uk and www.Skoolbo.ca and associated downloadable apps. 

The Skoolbo Privacy Policy should be read in conjunction with the Skoolbo Child Safety Policy; and the Skoolbo Terms and Conditions; which together form the full terms and conditions. 

From time to time Skoolbo may modify the Skoolbo Privacy Policy. Teachers and Parents will be notified of any updated policy and the most current version may be found here. 

  1. **What personal information does Skoolbo collect?**

Skoolbo collects the minimum amount of information possible for the effective learning management of the Child.

    * The first name (or pseudonym) of the Child, 
    * The initial of the surname (or pseudonym) of the Child, 
    * Month of Birth (not age) of the Child, 
    * Audio recording of the Child for spelling, vocabulary analysis and narration, 
    * School name, 
    * Class name, 
    * Teacher name, 
    * Teacher email, 
    * Parent name 
    * Parent email 

  2. **Right to Anonymity and Pseudonymity**
    * All users have the right to anonymity and pseudonymity. It is perfectly acceptable for pseudonyms to be used. Any pseudonyms must be reasonable and not vulgar or rude in nature or they will be removed.

  3. **What personal information does Skoolbo NOT collect?**

Skoolbo does NOT collect personally identifiable information of the Child such as:

    * Physical address; 
    * Email; 
    * Telephone number; 
    * A persistent identifier that can be used to recognise a user over time and across different websites or online services; 
    * A photograph, video file, 
    * Geolocation information sufficient to identify street name and name of a city or town 

  4. **What Skoolbo collects while the User is using the Skoolbo Services**
    * Results, audio recording and scores from the educational games. 
    * Usage statistics within the various sections of the Skoolbo services. 
    * While using the Skoolbo Services Skoolbo automatically collects and records certain information such as the User’s unique device ID; the User’s hardware type; the User’s operating system (“OS”); and the User’s Internet Protocol (“IP”) address. This information is used solely to assist Skoolbo in troubleshooting and understanding usage trends. This information is anonymous and not personally identifiable. 
    * Skoolbo does not record any information on the User when the User is not signed in to the Skoolbo Services. 

  5. **What Skoolbo does with the information it gathers**
    * The Child’s results are shared with the Parent, the Teacher and School Administrator. 
    * The Skoolbo Services uses multiplayer games. Multiplayer games share with the other players information such as the Child’s first name; the Child’s school and State/Territory or Country; the Child’s result from the current game. 
    * The Skoolbo Services also use “Leaderboards” and “Newsfeeds” which highlight outstanding performances by the Child. The Leaderboards and News Feeds contain such items as the Child’s first name; the Child’s school; the Child’s score or award. 
    * Skoolbo collects audio data from the children for testing spelling, word pronunciation, narrating books and answering questions. Skoolbo uses third parties such as [Google Cloud API](https://cloud.google.com/speech/) and [Soapbox Labs](http://www.soapboxlabs.com/) to process the audio files. 
    * Skoolbo does not sell, distribute or lease the User’s personal information to third parties unless Skoolbo has the User’s permission or are required by law to do so. 
    * Skoolbo analyses the aggregated data on the system to improve its services. No personally identifiable information is used for this purpose. 
    * Skoolbo shares anonymised data with its educational partners. This information is for research purposes which are ultimately designed to improve learning outcomes. No personally identifiable information is shared. 
    * Skoolbo reserves the right to share or sell the aggregated data on the system to other third parties. No personally identifiable information is used for this purpose. 

  6. **Security**
    * Skoolbo is committed to ensuring that the User’s information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, Skoolbo has put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information Skoolbo collects online.
    * Skoolbo uses global cloud services such as [Microsoft Windows Azure](http://www.windowsazure.com/en-us/services/cloud-services/), [Amazon Web Services](https://aws.amazon.com/) in particular and [Amazon Simple Email](https://aws.amazon.com/ses/), [Alibaba Cloud services](https://www.alibabacloud.com/) for the storage of data and general cloud services. All of these Cloud services providers are global companies with robust security systems in place.
    * Skoolbo uses [MailChimp](https://mailchimp.com/) for the sending of emails to the Parent and the Teacher. Mailchimp is recognized as a leader in email delivery services. 
    * Skoolbo uses [Webengage](https://webengage.com/) to support customer services. 

  7. **How Skoolbo uses cookies**
    * A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on the User’s computer’s hard drive. The file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic. 
    * Skoolbo uses traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps Skoolbo analyse data about web page traffic and improve the Skoolbo Services in order to tailor it to customer needs. Skoolbo only uses this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system. 
    * A cookie in no way gives Skoolbo access to the User’s computer or any information about the User, other than the data the User chooses to share with Skoolbo. 
    * The User can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but the User can usually modify browser setting to decline cookies. This may prevent the User from taking full advantage of Skoolbo Services. 

  8. **How Skoolbo uses web beacons**
    * Skoolbo may collect information using web beacons. Web beacons or “gifs”, are electronic images that may be used on Skoolbo website or in Skoolbo emails. Skoolbo may use web beacons to deliver cookies, count visits and to tell if an email has been opened and acted upon.

  9. **Links to other websites**
    * Any links to third party websites located on Skoolbo services are provided for the User’s convenience only. 
    * Skoolbo takes all reasonable steps to ensure any links to third party websites are appropriate. Skoolbo is not responsible for the content on any linked third party website. The User is encouraged to notify Skoolbo at [info@skoolbo.com](mailto:info@skoolbo.com) if there are any inappropriate links on Skoolbo services 

  10. **Correction of Personal Information**
    * Users have the right to access and correct any Personal Information contained on Skoolbo. 
    * In most circumstances this will be done directly by the Parent; Teacher or School Administrator on the Skoolbo site. 
    * Users may also email and request changes to be made. 
    * Changes of Personal information will apply to both Skoolbo services and related third parties such as Microsoft Windows Azure and Amazon Simple Email. 
    * Changes of Personal Information will occur within 72 hours. 

  11. **Removal of Personal Information**
    * Users have the right to have all Personal Information removed from Skoolbo services. 
    * Users may email [info@skoolbo.com](mailto:info@skoolbo.com) to request removal. 
    * Removal of Personal Information will apply to both Skoolbo services and related third parties such as Microsoft Windows Azure and Mailchimp. 
    * Removal of Personal Information will occur within 72 hours. 

  12. **Removal of inactive accounts**
    * Account deactivation. A user account is deemed to be inactive if there has been no login or usage during a 12 month period or if the student account lacks the parental necessary consent. A teacher account is deemed inactive if there has been no login or usage during a 12 month period. A parent (family) account is deemed inactive if there has been no login or usage during a 12 month period. Once an account has been inactive for 12 months it is removed from the Skoolbo system and all data deleted.
